Prabhjot Singh

510-509-5935 | pjsingh1359@zohomail.com | Fremont, CA | LinkedIn | GitHub | Portfolio

SUMMARY

Passionate Software Engineer with 1 year of experience currently building an application to aid African citizens get easier access to affordable produce and to help farmers have more ownership in their products and sales. Graduated from a 1000+ hour 6-month long intensive boot camp where I used React, Flask, SQL, and more to build 3 full stack projects.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

React, React Native, Next.js, Redux, JavaScript, Python, Ruby, Flask, Django, Tailwind, Git, CSS, SQL, AWS

PROJECTS

FriendZone June 2023

Facebook clone where users can post and interact with others.

Live | GitHub

- Collaborative project employing contemporary development approaches like agile methodology and incorporating widely adopted tools such as React, Flask, and AWS S3 to craft a user-friendly application.
- Developed the social feed feature to closely align with Facebook's design, empowering users with the capability to create, edit, delete, and comment on posts.

Zesty July 2023

Etsy clone where users can purchase items and create listings.

Live | GitHub

- Developed secure user authentication using BCrypt hashing in Python backend with React auth routes for enhanced security.
- Engineered the database, back-end routes, and front-end layout for the application.

Tripbnb May 2023

Airbnb soft clone where users can book, review, and manage spot listings

<u>Live</u> | <u>GitHub</u>

- Employing React, Node, Express, and Sequelize, I prioritized an impeccable UI design that harnessed the
 potential of Flexbox and Grid to ensure a sleek layout.
- Enabled users to view, review, book, and manage listings through the listings page for a comprehensive user experience.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Developer

Aug 2023 - Present

CUBESEED AFRICA, Lagos, Nigeria

- Engineered the front and back end of the marketplace using Next.js and Django
- Aided in developing a dashboard for people to become farmers, plan out their production, gain investors, and ultimately cut out the middle man and make produce more affordable to African citizens.

Software Engineer Intern

May 2022 - Feb 2023

LiveStockCity, Mount Solon, Virginia

- Collaborated with the back-end team to seamlessly integrate user sign-up, login, and social feed functionality.
- Developed features within the social feed that allow users to like and comment on posts, enhancing user engagement by 15%, and fostering a vibrant and engaging social media experience within the app.

Amazon Warehouse Ambassador

Sep 2014 - Sep 2018

Amazon, Newark, CA

- Led a high-performing team that achieved a remarkable 10% increase in productivity through seamless and prompt delivery of customer packages.
- Exemplary collaboration with managers to efficiently process packages, supervise workers, and maintain exceptional quality standards, while promptly addressing any operational challenges or issues.

EDUCATION

Full Stack Developer | Certificate Associates | Psychology App Academy – 2023 Ohlone College – 2019